MARC H. WEINER

Lead Software Engineer, UX Architect, R&D

mhweiner.com linkedin.com/in/mhweiner github.com/mhweiner mhweiner234@gmail.com

With over 15 years of experience, I lead cross-functional teams that design and build award-winning applications, driven by research and using a pragmatic, iterative approach. I enjoy problem solving, process and efficiency optimization, R&D, and working a collaborative environment.

EXPERIENCE

Ciro, New York, NY Founder, CTO

06/2016 - 04/2017

Designed and developed simple, UX-centric, Agile team collaboration tool. https://ciroapp.com

Design and full-stack development. Fully responsive, real-time, custom compositional Javascript SPA front-end, with PHP7 HMVC REST API back-end. Running on CentOS/Apache/Memcached/DO/Docker. Custom NodeJS build process. Focus on UX and performance.

Advizr, New York, NY

04/2014 - 05/2016

Director of Front-End Technology, UX

Led the architecture, UX, design, and front-end development of award-winning application from the ground up, with limited resources. https://advizr.com

- Recognized as Best Client Facing Technology of 2015 by FPPad.
- Pre-revenue to over \$2M/yr within 2 years.
- Led and helped build a small team of developers, freelancers, and managed a creative agency. Made key hires.
- Transitioned company to an iterative Agile development process.
- BA/UX/AI, requirement gathering, wire-framing, and prototyping.
- Led architecture & development of flexible custom component-based MVVM Javascript front-end SPA.
- Helped transition company from legacy MVC .NET to modern REST API architecture.

Marvel Entertainment, New York, NY Lead Front-End Software Engineer

02/2013 – 10/2013

Contract

Led R&D and architecture of Marvel.com, one of the first high-traffic, content-rich, fully-responsive websites.

- Led design, research, and development strategy, architecture, meetings, and set standards, methodologies and conventions. Used "device agnostic feature-based responsive design" methodology which is standard practice today.
- Worked closely with design team to ensure delivery of high quality work within constraints.
- Invented and developed new technology which allowed us to post-process sass files, in conjunction with a device detection system to dramatically reduce payload size, while still allowing a single source code.
- Major technical challenges included R&D, payload size, slower network speeds and mobile devices, responsive "high-res" content, performance & optimizations, legacy browser support, mobile optimization, ad integration, and a tight deadline.
- Javascript, HTML5/CSS3, PHP and Ruby.

Marc H. Weiner Consulting, New York, NY

Founder, CTO, Lead, APM

01/2001 - 04/01/2014

Led small cross-functional teams deliver wireframes, designs, and full-stack, cross-platform development for startups and Fortune 500 companies. Worked across medical, industrial, logistics, education, and retail industries. Performed BA/requirement gathering. Worked with mostly LAMP stack, custom HTML5/CSS3/Javascript, Cordova, and real-time systems.

Remedy Systems, New York, NY

08/2012 - 11/2012

Director of User Experience, Senior Software Engineer

Led UX architecture, design and FE-development of revolutionary medical application designed to prevent hospital re-admissions. Helped transition company to iterative Agile development process, full-stack software development, sprint planning, and wrote specs. Mentored junior UI designers and developers.

HTML5/CSS3/Javascript, PHP w/ Symfony2 MVC backend. Focus on UX, TDD, automated testing, and reliability.

comiXology (Amazon), New York, NY Senior Front-End Web Developer

11/2011 - 01/2012

Contract

Helped build HTML5 e-commerce comic bookstore from the ground up for a streamlined shopping and checkout experience. Promoted consistency, cross-browser compatibility, and best practices. HTML5/CSS3/jQuery, Agile, progressive enhancement. http://comixology.com

DigitasLBI, New York, NY Front-End Web Developer 10/2005 - 01/2006

Contract

Developed micro-sites for American Express, Delta, The New York Times, and Time Warner.

SKILLS Software Architecture, Technical Strategy, R&D, Full-stack development, Process Design, Scalable Systems Architecture, Responsive Design, Mobile & Cross-Platform development, Performance Optimization, CI, Build Tooling & Release Engineering, Automated Systems, PHP7, Javascript (ES5/ES6), HTML5/CSS3, Java, C++, Python, scripting, Node.js, React.js, Cordova, git, MySQL/NoSQL, Docker, Linux, Strategic Hiring, Team Building, Cross-Functional Team Leadership, UI/UX Design, Wireframing/Prototyping, Invision, Adobe CS, Sketch & more

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Private Pilot Certificate (SEL) — Federal Aviation Administration, 2015 Computer Science, Aerospace Engineering — University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY, 2005